When the world closed its eyes, he opened his arms.
Hotel Rwanda is a drama, history, war film directed by Terry George.
Inspired by true events, this film takes place in Rwanda in the 1990s when more than a million
Tutsis were killed in a genocide that went mostly unnoticed by the rest of the world.
Hotel owner Paul Rusesabagina houses over a thousand refuges
in his hotel in attempt to save their lives.
Paul Rusesabagina, played by Don Cheadle.
Tatiana Rusesabagina, played by Sophie Okonedo.
Colonel Oliver, played by Nick Nolte.
General Bizimungu, played by Fana Mokoena.
Dube, played by Desmond Dube.
George Rutaganda, played by Hakeem Kae-Kazim.
Hotel Rwanda is a 2004 biographical historical drama film
co-written and directed by Terry George.
It was adapted from a screenplay by George and Keir Pearson, and stars Don Cheadle
and Sophie Okonedo as hotelier Paul Rusesabagina and his wife Tatiana.
The film depicts Rusesabagina's efforts to save the lives of his family and more than 1,500 other refugees by providing them with
shelter in the besieged Hôtel des Mille Collines during the Rwandan genocide, which occurred during the spring of 1994.
Hotel Rwanda explores genocide, political corruption,
and the repercussions of violence.
The film was a co-production between United Artists and Lions Gate Films, and was commercially
distributed by United Artists theatrically and by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer for home media.
Hotel Rwanda premiered in theaters in limited release in the United States on 22 December 2004 and in
wide release on 4 February 2005, grossing more than $23 million in domestic ticket sales.
It earned an additional $10 million in business through international release to
top out at a combined total of nearly $34 million in gross revenue.
The film was critically acclaimed and on many of the year's Top 10 lists.
It was nominated for multiple awards, including Academy Award nominations for Best Actor
(Cheadle), Best Supporting Actress (Okonedo), and Best Original Screenplay.
The film explores themes of rwanda, refugee, refugee camp, tutsi, militia.
The tone is emotional.